# Akanksha Sharma (1) Featured

Software Engineer seeking roles in Software Development, Application Programming, System Analysis, Requirement Gathering, Client Interaction, Project Management, Java, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, JIRA, MySQL, MongoDB



Current Designation: Software Engineer Total Experience: 4 Year(s) 5 Month(s) Current Company: Claritus Highest Degree: MCA [Computers]

Current Location: Gurgaon

Pref. Location: Gurgaon, Delhi / NCR, Noida

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: Software Engineer, Software Developer, Software Development, Application Programming, System

Analysis, Requirement Gathering, Client Interaction, Project

Management, Java, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, JIRA, MySQL, MongoDB

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 20-Jan-21 Last Modified: 20-Jan-21

# Summary

4.5 years of experience in all phases of Software Development Life Cycle.

Experienced in client interactions, requirement gathering and analysis.

Experienced in working on Spring and Hibernate Frameworks.

Extensive experience in developing RESTful web services.

Decent know how of RDBMS and NoSQL database such as MySQL, Oracle, IBM Informix, PostgreSQL and MongoDB.

# Work Experience

Claritus as Software Engineer

Sep 2019 to Till Date

Javelin Organization: G4S IT Services October 2019 - present **Duration: 7months** 

Software Engineer Role(s)

Brief Description Javelin will provide a fully integrated end-to-end solution for Secure Solutions covering Operations, Finance, HR, IT and Procurement - all process linked together for the first time in G4S. It will be globally scalable and applicable with strategic intent to implement this system in all G4S business around the world, and the system is being designed with this ultimate goal in mind.

Responsibilities Requirement Analysis, functional/technical requirements.

- Code enhancement, documentation, development.
- Testing, code merging.
- Birt Report Design and Development.

Modules Petrol and Response

Reporting

Environment Spring boot, Java, Hibernate, mongoDB, BIRT Reports

# Yamaha Motor Solutions (India) - YMSLI as Software Engineer

Jan 2016 to Sep 2019

Organization: YMSLI May 2019 - September 2019 RevNavi

Role(s) Software Engineer

Brief Description RevNavi is a complete golf course management solution that includes an iOS application for carts with navigation and game management capabilities, a web application for live tracking of carts and other management features such as organizing tournaments, etc.

Designed and developed REST API. Responsibilities \*

- Perform regression tests, release and deploy builds.
- Report on progress and issues via checkpoint meetings with client.

Environment Java, Spring Boot, Hibernate, Swagger, Bootstrap, AWS, FireBase, Gradle

Organization: YMSLI November 2016 - April 2019 Duration: 2 Years 5 Months **GFAST** Role(s) Software Engineer

Brief Description An existing desktop application based on Sybase Power Builder to be converted in Web based spring application. Used for managing purchases, system control, stocks for Yamaha. Functions being divided and working in collaboration with YMSLI (India), YMSLJ (Japan), YMSLX (China).

Requirement Analysis, functional/technical requirements.

- Code enhancement, documentation, development.
- Mentoring team members.
- Testing, code merging, deployment.

IBM Informix Server, Spring boot, Java, JPA, JQXGrid

YNA G1 - G2 Convertor Organization: YMSLI January 2016 - October 2016 Duration: 10 Months Role(s) Software Engineer

Brief Description YNA is a framework that Yamaha has developed to facilitate and expedite process of creating web based applications. Generation 1 (G1) was used to build their mainstream applications such as Pymidol (dealer management), inventory management, etc. The technology stack for G1 is running out of support in 2019 hence existing applications need to be ported to new generation G2 based on Spring Boot, Spring Data and SiteMesh UI framework. This porting of existing applications called for a need of building a comprehensive tool that would convert existing code to YNA G2 framework with minimum possible human intervention.

Responsibilities \* Research and analyze ways to convert code from one technology to another.

- Design solution and document conversion procedure for other developers to follow.
- Creating support library for converted code.
- Optimize and improvise conversion of framework related codebase and expediting conversion process.

Extensive use of OOP concepts helped in designing the solution.

- Porting all except UI framework based code was practically viable with minimal human intervention.
- Project was reviewed and appreciated by offshore (Japan) team as well.

Environment OOP concepts, Java, STS

#### **Education**

UG: BCA (Computers) from Punjab Technical University in 2013

PG: MCA (Computers) from Guru Gobind Singh Indraprastha University (GGSIU) in 2016

#### IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
Java Enterprise Edition , BIRT			
Java, CSS, HTML , JavaScript			
MySQL, Oracle, PostgreSQL, IBM Informix			
Mongodb			
Eclipse, STS, MySQL Workbench			
pgAdmin, Server Studio, Mongo 3T			
JIRA, GIT, Bitbucket, SVN			
Spring MVC, Spring Boot			

# Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak	

https://freesearch.naukri.com/preview/printResume?uname=0421899a802e4f18c7326cd7d6975ee05d0c0f531c1258175243135d5e...1/22/2021

English	Expert
Hindi	Expert

### **Affirmative Action**

Category: General

Physically Challenged: No

### **Work Authorization**

Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time